A Guide to the Papers of Margaret and John Travers Moore, 1914-1994
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Margaret and John Travers Moore 1914-1994
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11161
ca. 8,000 items (27 Hollinger boxes; 11 linear shelf feet)
This collection consists of the papers of Margaret (1903-1984) and John Travers Moore (1908-1994), ca. 1914-1994, ca. 8,000 items (27 Hollinger boxes; 11 linear shelf feet), poets and authors who published their material in a wide variety of journals, magazines, and books from the 1930's until John Moore's death in 1994. The papers include published and unpublished literary manuscripts, correspondence, audio and video recordings, artwork, memorabilia, bound volumes, photographs, books (transferred to the Rare Books Division), printed material, newsclippings, scrapbooks, certificates and awards, genealogy notes, several philatelic covers, a bust of John Travers Moore and paintings by Robert J. Smith, a friend of Moore's, and sheet music by Moore.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions
Acquisition Information
The Moore papers were bequeathed to the University of Virginia Library by John Travers Moore, Hendersonville, North Carolina, through his executor E.K. Morley, on December 5, 1994.
Biographical/Historical Information
Information about the life and publications of Margaret and John Travers Moore can be found throughout the collection but particularly in the Memorabilia Series in the Introduction to the Files (Box 25) compiled by John T. Moore, 1984-1994, which reveals much about how Moore viewed their work and their relationships to publishers, friends, and family. About eleven hundred letters listed in this introduction were housed in photographic albums but these were removed and interfiled for preservation purposes. Other files with personal information include: Certificates and Awards (Box 24), Genealogy and Family History (Box 24), Photographs (Box 25), Newsclippings (Box 25), Scrapbooks of Press Releases and Poems published in Periodicals (Box 26), and the oversize photograph album arranged in rough chronological order and identified by Moore.
Published sources include Contemporary Authors (1995), The Marquis Who's Who in America, page 2435 (1994) and Who's Who in American Women (1982).
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of the papers of Margaret (1903-1984) and John Travers Moore (1908-1994), ca. 1914-1994, ca. 8,000 items (27 Hollinger boxes; 11 linear shelf feet), poets and authors who published their material in a wide variety of journals, magazines, and books from the 1930's until John Moore's death in 1994. The papers include published and unpublished literary manuscripts, correspondence, audio and video recordings, artwork, memorabilia, bound volumes, photographs, books (transferred to the Rare Books Division), printed material, newsclippings, scrapbooks, certificates and awards, genealogy notes, several philatelic covers, a bust of John Travers Moore and paintings by Robert J. Smith, a friend of Moore's, and sheet music by Moore.
The manuscripts series (Boxes 1-14) contains mostly unpublished manuscripts. Those that have been published include: All Along the Way, The First Moon Landing, How Can I Show You God, Jeannette?, The Little Band and the Inaugural Parade, Pepito's Journey, Pepito's Speech at the United Nations, Pepito's World, Sappho's Poetry, and The Story of Silent Night.
The correspondence series (Boxes 15-23) contains correspondence with editors and publishers, friends and family, and others, arranged alphabetically by folder title. Persons with their own correspondence folders include: Jean Pierre and Muriel de Chambrun (friends of the Moores for almost forty years); James E. Creekman (Moore's dismissed attorney); Harris and Hazel Huston (some of his oldest friends; Harris attended law school with Moore and served in the American Embassy at Curacao, Netherlands Antilles); Tina Miller (editor at D.C. Heath and Company); nephew Jerry Moore (writes concerning Moore family genealogy and news); Margaret and John Moore to each other; Margaret and John Moore to their parents; George and Peggy Rumberger; artist and friend Robert Smith and Nancy Mackey (his daughter), see also drawings by Smith (Box 24) and list of large paintings at the end of the guide; and the University of Virginia, chiefly Edmund Berkeley, concerning Moore's intention of making the University the repository for his literary work.
The correspondence, 1929-1988, with George and Peggy Rumberger, Margaret's brother and sister-in-law, contains fourteen letters and photographs, 1944-1945, concerning the service of George Rumberger in the Corps of Engineers, U.S. Army, in Burma as a master sergeant during World War II. Rumberger won a citation for the Bronze Star for his advance planning for the Stillwell Road. Other items present in the Rumberger folder include a map of North Burma with Rumberger's notes about his itinerary and the area written in the margins. He also describes his experiences in Burma and India, mentioning riding elephants, hunting tigers, the deprivations and hardships of the soldiers, the Ledo Road, the dense and isolated jungles, and a Buddhist school in Burma. The folders of correspondence with individuals is the best source for personal information about the Moore's missing from the other files.
Topics with separate folders include: banking & savings bonds (Box 15); contracts (Box 15); copyrights (Box 16); Ireland as retirement location (Box 17); lectures (Box 17); the Nobel Peace Award nomination for Pepito and the United Nations trilogy (Box 18); Perfection Form Company Poetry Poster Series, etc. (Box 19); publishers and editors (Box 19); Spoken Arts publisher Arthur Luce Klein (Box 20); reprints & permissions (Box 20-21); royalties (Box 22); social security (Box 22); and Moore's controversy with the Walt Whitman Center for Arts and Humanities (Box 23).
Manuscripts and published books with their own correspondence folders include: Around the Corner from Our House(Box 15) which records the long term disagreement of John Travers Moore with Mr. and Mrs. Harry Lerner of Lerner Publications and Carolrhoda Books about the publication of Around the Corner from Our House and All Along the Way; copyright concerns regarding The Story of Silent Night(Box 16); the composition and promotion of The Little Band and the Inaugural Parade as a musical play, including correspondence with Carol Davis and Denise Adams (Box 17); the publication of the Pepito and the United Nations trilogy by the United Nations (Boxes 18- 19); Moore's work on the World War II publication Plane Facts(Box 19); Moore's attempt to publish his manuscripts "Portrait of America" (Box 19); "The Road" formerly titled "Jingalong" (Box 21); "Sinmin (Lord Elephant), which includes some wonderful letters from Burma, describing how to capture elephants (Box 22); "Sports Poems" (Box 22); and correspondence concerning Moore's classic children's book The Story of Silent Night.
Organization
The papers have been arranged in three large series: I) Manuscripts (Boxes 1-14); II) Correspondence Files (Boxes 15-23); and III) Memorabilia and Miscellaneous Material. The Correspondence Series retains the original reverse chronological order of the files.
General Correspondence Files
A Correspondence
Manuscripts mentioned include: "April Fool's Day," "And So Was the Cat," At the Foot of the Manger"At Night," "Among These Hills" & "Picture Poems," How Can I Show You God, Jeannette?, "The Easter Bup," "A Star for the Christ Child," "At the Margins," "The Astronomer" "Easter Nightingale," "The Voice" and "April Rain"
Correspondents include:
Ruth Cantor, Literary Agent (1966 Oct 7; 1964 Jun 23)
Ruth Hill Viguers, Editor of The Horn Book(1965 Feb 25)
Royal D. Frey, Air Force Museum re Plane Facts(1963 Dec 21)
Edith Mackin, The Authors Guild (1959 Feb 4)
Virginia Sobotka (1959 Jul 23-Aug 6; 1958 Jan 9 & 21, Dec 18)
Laura Harris (1952 Oct 2-1953 Oct 13)
Major Harry E. Shubart, Army Air Forces (1944 Aug 5)
Anne Stoddard (1943 Mar 26)
B Correspondence
Manuscripts mentioned include: "The Bicycle," "Blinky," "Minnows," "The Blessing of the Padre," "The Bachelor's Ballad," "The Beetle," "The Butterfly," and an unsubmitted draft of a "National Code of Book Reviewers"
Correspondents include:
Karl Maslowski & Donald Borror re bird behavior (1971 Jul-Aug)
Paschal Boland, The Grail(1955 Jun 11)
C Correspondence
Manuscripts mentioned include: "The Cardinal" "The Child," "Christmas Carol," Cinnamin Seed,"The Cincinnati Waltz," "City Lights," "Clem Takes A Wife," "Close to the Sky," "The Coat," "The Colt," "Comparisons," "The Contest," "Cooks Bookmarks," "Crocodile Tears," "Quiet Is My Love."
Correspondents include:
Capital University (1972 Mar 15; 1981 Mar 4)
Harry Carlson, Fraternity Records (1972 Feb 29)
Miriam Chaikin (1970 May 12)
Chicago Tribune re Story of Silent Night reprint (1976 Jan 29)
Congressman James McClure Clarke (1983 Apr 18)
Marion Belden Cook (1951)
Steve Allen and others, CBS, re song "Quiet is My Love" (1951- 1952)
Congressman Bill Hendon re Social Security (1982 May 12; 1985 Oct 24)
Ellen Sarrah, Good Housekeeping(1982 Jun 8)
D-E-F Correspondence
Manuscripts mentioned include: "The Deeps," "Dirge for the Old Year," "Easter Song," "The Echo," "Everywhere and In Between," "Farm Mother," "Favorites," "The First King of Israel," "The First Moon Landing," "Poems," and "There's Motion Everywhere"
Correspondents include:
Dayton's Women's Press Club (1942 Nov 9)
University of Dayton art exhibit re Robert J. Smith (1967 Sep 11)
Distinguished People A-H
Neil A. Armstrong
Robert Braine, composer
Pearl S. Buck
William F. Buckley, Jr.
Barbara Bush
Jimmy Carter
Nathalia Crane
Frank Crumit
Phil Donahue (letter to, only)
M.R. "Bob" Evans, Honorable Order of Kentucky Colonels
Robert Frost
Paul W. Gallico
C. Hugo Grimm
Helen Hayes
Daniel Whitehead Hicky
Ralph Hodgson
Governor James E. Holshouser, Jr., North Carolina
J. Edgar Hoover
Hubert H. Humphrey
Governor James B. Hunt, Jr., North Carolina
Distinguished People I-Z
Governor Ruby Laffoon, Kentucky
Senator H.C. Lodge, Jr.
Henry Loomis, The White House
J.B. Montini, Vatican Secretary of State, (later Pope Paul VI)
Patricia Nixon
Louise G. Owen
Pope John XXIII (form letter)
Oscar Rasbach, composer
Monsignor G.B. Re (for Pope John Paul II)
Mrs. Vernon Reid, Deputy Assistant to Governor James A. Rhodes, Ohio
Marthe Ruspoli
[Samuel C.] Stu, Archbishop of Chicago
Senator Robert A. Taft
Deems Taylor
Jean Thomas, The Traipsin' Woman
Boyce A. Whitmore, Mayor of Hendersonville
Walter Winchell (photostat)
Family Correspondence
This includes correspondence from all relatives except their parents, Jerry Moore, and George Rumberger who all have a separate folder. Correspondents include: Aunt June Moore, Rose Julia, Gould and Rose, Shirley and Sharon Hatfield, Jean and Edith, George H. Lee, Mark Moore, Helen (sister of J.T.M.) and Jim, and Lucille Barlow-Schmitt.
G Correspondence
Manuscripts mentioned include: "Favorites," "The Goblin Garden," "God's Wonderful World," "Going Up," "Gratitude," "Green Fingers," "Reading Games," "Rondel in Pinafore," "Thank You, God"
Correspondents include:
Licia Gaut-Correll, with article re Moore "A Lifetime In Literature" (1991 Sep 10)
Ginn & Company, Faith & Freedom Series (1958 Sep 16 & 23, Nov 28)
Cyril Clemens (1955 Jan 18; 1958 Aug 22; n.d.)
H Correspondence
Manuscripts mentioned include: "Calico Carnival," "The Hallowe'en Goblin," "Heritage," "Hidden Garden," "Homeward," "Hours of May," "The House," and "Sun Patterns"
Correspondents include:
Henry Holt and Company (1991)
I-L Correspondence
Manuscripts mentioned include: "Just-Before Times," The Little Band and the Inaugural Parade(Junior Literary Guild Selection in 1968), "Little Zo," "The Lyrist of Lesbos," "The Last Flower," They Saw Him Fly,"Wind in the Grass," Little Stories About the Saints, Big Saints, Little Saints,"Lanterns," "They Legion of the Dead," and "The Lost Land"
Correspondents include:
Life Experience School (1986 Jun 11)
Bernard Knox, Center for Hellenic Studies (1978 Sep 18; 1979 Jun 18, 22, Oct 31)
Derek C. Bok (1978 Oct 2, Nov 4)
Virginia Sobotka (1957 Dec 12)
Philip Mahin, The Grail(1955 Aug 3)
Paschal Boland The Grail(1953 Jun 1)
Margaret Cousins (1943 Dec 7)
M Correspondence
Manuscripts mentioned include: "The Multitudinous Caravan," "Mountain Ballads," "Moonlight," "The May Basket," "The Child," "The Message," "March Came in Like a Lion"
Correspondents include:
Ingrid and Bob Margrave (1984 Sep 4; [1985 Jul 1]; 1988 Apr 27)
Herbert S. Bailey, Princeton University Press (1982-1983) controversy re "The Multitudinous Caravan"
N-O Correspondence
Manuscripts mentioned include: "The First Moon Landing," "The Gifts," "New England Poems," "Northern Holiday," "OH -H-H!" "The Old Umbrella," "Olivet," On Cherry Tree Hill,"Other Singers," "Portrait of America," and The Three Tripps(source for ideas, 1971 Feb 19)
Correspondents include:
Cyril Clemens (n.d.)
NASA (1979 Jul 6)
National Catholic Welfare Conference (1942 Jan 21)
New York Statue Committee & Cosmopolis Inscription (1981 Oct 1 & attached)
Cletus E. Oberst (1987 May 19, Jun 23)
Oddo Publishing Company re inability to publish "Guess What I Am" (1971-1975)
Ohio Historical Society (1970 Oct 28)
Our Lady of Cincinnati College (1956 May 13)
P Correspondence
Manuscripts mentioned include: "Autumn," "Bonny Bugs," "A Child's Christmas Carol," "Cloud Horses," "The Computer That Didn't," "Everywhere & In-Between," "First Flight," "From Sea to Sea," "Funday Funnies," "Goblin Garden," "Go-Things," "Halfway," "The Halloween Pumpkin," "The Last Flower," The Little Band and the Inaugural Parade,"Let Me Live Dangerously," "Love Lyrics," "My Skateboard," "Night World," "Nooks and Crannies," "Peaceful the Dark," "Peanuts for Miss Bedelia," "Peppercorns," "Peter Polter Guyst," "The Peter Pan Heart," "A Pixie on Main Street," "The Place," "Poem for Editors," "Poetry of Flight," "Portrait of America," "Rondel in Pinafore," "Sputnik," "The Stranger," "Talking Weather," "Voices of the Wild," "Wee Wings," "Weeds," and "The Whisper"
Correspondents include:
Atheneum policy (1979 Dec 3 & 27)
National Science Teachers Association & the insect poems (1983 Feb 4)
Eleanor Nichols, McGraw-Hill (1964)
John Frederick Nims (1980 Jul 31)
"Poethaven," notes re (n.d.)
Poetry magazine (1984 Dec 3 & 13; 1985 Jan 22 & 28)
Henry Charles Suter & plagiarism charge (1943 Sep-Oct)
Charlotte Zolotow (1979 Oct 23, Nov 8, Dec 4)
Q-R Correspondence
Manuscripts mentioned include: "Bun Bun," "Quiet is My Love," "Petals," "The Rabbit Who Wanted To Play," "The Race," "The Rebel," "The Recollections," "Reptiliana," "The Robin," "The Robin's Song," and "The Round Book"
Correspondents include:
Regnery Gateway, Inc. re anthology of 101 poems idea (1982-1983)
Charles Roush re poetry writing (1968 Apr-Jun)
S Correspondence
Manuscripts mentioned include: "Astronauts," "Cosmonaut," "First Moon Landing," "Harvest," "Nooks and Crannies," "Rhymes and Chimes," "The Santa Claus Party," "Silent Majority Speaks," "Silly Milly," Sing-Along Sary,"Sliding," "Snow," "So Many Springs," "Songs of Shadows," "Sound-Alikes," "Spring Comes to the Hillside," "Sputnik, Blast-Off," "Stand Tall," "Strange Insects and Animals," and "Sun Patterns"
Correspondents include:
Arizona reminiscences of J.T. Moore (1968 Mar 1)
National Review(1979- 1980)
Smithsonian Air & Space Museum (1969 Nov 10, Dec 4,8, 11; and 1979 [Jan?] 19*
Statue of Liberty Song (1984 Mar-Jun)
Julia Louise Sutor (1970 Apr 21)
T Correspondence
Manuscripts mentioned include: On Cherry Tree Hill,"Talky Bird," "The Teacher," "They Saw Him Fly," "The Three Sons," The Three Tripps,"To Be In Love," "Trees," "Turtles," "Two Song," and "Two Tears for Ireland"
U-Z Correspondence
Manuscripts mentioned include: "The Affectionate Bee," "Bird Language," "The First Moon Landing," "Holiday, Happy Day," "Liberty Shall Stand," "The Little World," "The Turtle," "The View," "Voices of the Wild," "Wallflowers," "Water Walkers," We Are Like Wine,"Where I Live," "The Whisper," "Work," and "A Young World of Poetry"
Correspondents include:
Little, Brown Company controversy over "A Young World of Poetry" manuscript (1982-1983)
War Department, Army Air Forces Air Technical Service Command, Hq., ATSC, Wright Field, Dayton, Ohio - Moore's record of service (1945 Nov 5)
Xavier University, Margaret Moore employed there 1947-1967 (1955 Jan 7; 1956 Mar 22; 1958 Jun 3; 1959 Feb 2; Jul 22; 1963 Oct 16; 1969 Feb 1; 1972 Jan 5)
Zeta Tau Alpha Foundation (1973 Jan 4; 1980; 1993 Feb 5, Mar 17 & 21, Apr 2 & 7)
Contents List
- Manuscripts (Box 1-14)
  All manuscipts are by John Travers Moore unless otherwise noted
  - All Along the Way ca.1973 (Box 1)
  - America: The Masterpiece n.d. (Box 1)
  - Around the Corner from Our House ca. 1971 (Box 1)
  - At the Foot of the Manger ca. 1971 (Box 1)
  - Barky and Friends n.d. (Box 1)
  - A Bit-About n.d. (Box 1)
  - Bonny Bugs 1981, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Christmas album 1976 (Box 1)
  - The Computer That Didn't Give Up ca. 1982 (Box 1)
  - "Definition of a Poet" n.d. (Box 1)
  - Everywhere and In-Between ca. 1969 (Box 1)
  - The First King of Israel by Thomas Emmet Moore, Revised and Edited by John Travers Moore n.d., 2 folders (Box 2)
  - The First Moon Landing 1979 (Box 2)
  - The Four Seasons n.d. (Box 2)
  - Funday Funnies n.d., 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Funny Fellows 1981, n.d. (Box 2)
  - The Goblin Garden n.d. (Box 2)
  - Guess What I Am by Margaret Moore ca. 1971 (Box 2)
  - Holiday, Happy Day ca. 1977, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - The House Without A Name by Margaret Moore n.d. (Box 3)
  - How Can I Show You God, Jeannette? ca. 1950 (Box 3)
  - How Can I Show You God, Jeannette? [1950] Oct 6 (Box 3)
  - Inroads n.d. (Box 3)
  - It Might Have Been ca. 1982 (Box 3)
  - "A Letter to the World" n.d. (Box 3)
  - The Little Band and the Inaugural Parade ca. 1968 (Box 3)
  - The Little World n.d. (Box 3)
  - Little Zo 1969 (Box 3)
  - Love Lyrics ca. 1982, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Love Lyrics ca. 1982 (Box 4)
  - The Lyrist of Lesbos: A Play n.d. (Box 4)
  - Metropolia: Echoes of New York n.d. (Box 4)
  - The Milestone n.d.
  - Miniatures n.d., 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Miniatures II n.d., 2 folders (Box 4)
  - The Multitudinous Caravan ca. 1974, 3 folders (Box 5)
    including Carbon & Discards
  - The Night World ca.1979 (Box 5)
  - Nooks and Crannies by Margaret Moore ca. 1977 (Box 5)
  - Obie and Huk by Margaret and John Travers Moore n.d. (Box 5)
  - One Green Tree n.d. (Box 5)
  - Overtones n.d., 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Parodies of Famous Poems n.d. (Box 6)
  - Peanuts for Miss Bedelia by Margaret Moore ca. 1978 (Box 6)
  - Pepito's Journey 1986-1988, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Pepito's Speech at the United Nations by Margaret and John Travers Moore 1983 (Box 6)
  - Pepito's Speech at the United Nations(Re-Illustrated) by Margaret and John Travers Moore 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - Pepito's Speech at the United Nations Screenplay by Dan Bredemann 1990 (Box 6)
  - Pepito's World 1987-1988, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Pepito's World 1988, Galleys (Box 6)
  - Peter Polter Guyst ca. 1978 (Box 6)
  - A Pixie on Main Street ca. 1979, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - The Pocket-Hankerchief Wild by Margaret Moore 1977, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Poemettes n.d. (Box 7)
  - Poems by Margaret Moore n.d. (Box 7)
  - Poems (First Published) by Margaret Moore 1920, n.d. (Box 7)
    including Stories for Neighbors, "Such Funny Sights" & Background Material
  - Poems for the Young (Some Original Manuscripts) n.d. (Box 7)
  - Poems for the Young n.d. (Box 7)
    "Leftovers" or Discards from other poetry collections
  - Poems - General & Experimental n.d., 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Poems - Odds & Ends n.d. (Box 8)
  - Poems - Original Manuscripts n.d. (Box 8)
  - Poethaven: The Storybook House and Garden 1991 Apr 11 (Box 8)
  - The Poetry of Flight: A Picture History of Aviation n.d. (Box 8)
  - Poetry (Loose poems removed from the Albums) 1978-1994 (Box 8)
  - Quiet is my Love n.d. (Box 9)
  - Quill and Star: An Autobiography (with final editing) ca. 1988, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Quill and Star: An Autobiography 1988, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Quill and Star: An Autobiography n.d., 2 folders (Box 9)
    Carbon Copy
  - Quill and Star: An Autobiography n.d., 2 folders (Box 10)
  - The Road, formerly Jingalong 1993-1994, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - The Round Book n.d. (Box 10)
  - Sappo's Poetry(Paraphrase, Addition, Extension) ca. 1962-1979 (Box 10)
  - Silly Milly by Margaret Moore n.d. (Box 10)
  - Sinmin, Lord Elephant ca. 1978, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Song of the Road by Margaret and John Travers Moore n.d., 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Songs (Original Manusceipts) n.d. (Box 11)
  - Songs of Appalachia n.d., 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Songs of shadows (Sex in Verse), with illustrations by the author n.d. (Box 11)
  - Sound-Alikes, by Margaret and John Travers Moore n.d. (Box 11)
  - Sports Poems 1983, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Stories & Poetry (Experimental) by Margaret Moore n.d. (Box 12)
  - The Story of Silent Night(Original) 1965 (Box 12)
  - The Story of Silent Night printed in The Chicago Tribune1975 Dec 25 (Box 12)
  - The Story of Silent Night(For the Stage) 1986-1988 (Box 12)
  - Storyettes n.d. (Box 12)
  - Strange Insects and Animals 1985-1990 (Box 12)
  - Sun Patterns n.d., 2 folders (Box 13)
  - The Tangiers Cat n.d. (Box 13)
  - To Be in Love ca. 1976 (Box 13)
  - Together Poems by Margaret and John Travers Moore n.d. (Box 13)
  - Voices of the Wild ca. 1977 & 1990 (Box 13)
  - You Are Two People: O'Leary and Other Irish Poems n.d. (Box 13)
  - A Young World of Poetry (Original Worksheets) 1982 (Box 13)
  - A Young World of Poetry ca. 1982, 5 folders (Box 14)
- Correspondence Files (Box 15-23)
  - A - Correspondence 1943-1992 (Box 15)
  - Around the Corner From Our House 1971-1983, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - B - Correspondence 1937-1984, n.d. (Box 15)
  - B - Correspondence re Banking and Savings Bonds 1967-1992 (Box 15)
  - C - Correspondence 1938-1991, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Jean Pierre and Muriel de Chambrun 1965-1991, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Contracts 1950-1988, n.d. (Box 15)
  - Copyright 1931-1992, 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Copyright - The Story of Silent Nightca. 1962-1994 (Box 16)
  - D-E-F Correspondence 1921-1987 (Box 16)
  - James E. Creekman (Dismissed Attorney) 1983-1986 (Box 16)
  - Distinguished People: A-H 1934-1990 (Box 16)
  - Distinguished People: I-Z 1931-1986 (Box 16)
  - Family Correspondence 1955-1989 (Box 16)
  - "Fan" Letters 1956-1994, n.d. (Box 16)
  - G Correspondence 1926-1992 (Box 16)
  - H Correspondence 1940-1991 (Box 16)
  - Harris and Hazel Huston 1950-1989 (Box 16)
  - I-L Correspondence 1931-1994 (Box 16)
  - Ireland as a Retirement Location 1973-1979, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Lectures 1939-1966 (Box 17)
  - The Little Band and the Inaugural Parade: A Musical Play 1984-1991, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - M Correspondence 1920-1990 (Box 17)
  - Memoranda of John Travers Moore ca. 1983-1994, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Tina Miller 1983-1985 (Box 17)
  - Jerry Moore 1979-1991 (Box 17)
  - Margaret and John Moore 1927-1984, n.d., 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Margaret and John Moore - Letters to their parents 1926-1950, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Margaret Moore - Condolence Letters 1984 (Box 17)
  - N-O Correspondence 1942-1991 (Box 17)
  - Nobel Peace Award Nomination 1984-1990 (Box 18)
  - P Correspondence 1932-1993, n.d. (Box 18)
  - Pepito and the United Nations 1987-1993, 5 folders (Box 18)
  - Pepito and the United Nations 1971, 1982-1986, 4 folders (Box 19)
  - The Perfection Form Company Poetry Poster Series, etc. 1985-1991 (Box 19)
  - Plane Facts 1943-1945, 1965 (Box 19)
  - "Portrait of America" 1969-1970, 1983-1984 (Box 19)
  - Publishers and Editors 1969-1994 (Box 19)